Parmenion Koutsogeorgos

I am an Artificial Intelligence Engineer based in the Netherlands. I am currently working part-time for Cordys Analytics, a startup affiliated with the University Medical Center Utrecht which applies A.I. methods for the purpose of diagnosing heart disease from electrocardiograms (ECGs). At the same time, I am working on my thesis for the Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence at Maastricht University, researching the use of State-Space models (Mamba) trained on bio-acoustic data for the purpose of monitoring animal populations. I have a strong background in Mathematics, having completed a bachelor's and master's in Mathematics at the University of Cambridge. I am mainly interested in A.I. with applications to engineering and healthcare.

Professional experience

Cordys Analytics Utrecht, NL

A.I. Engineer

Sep. 2024 - Today

After completing a 6-month internship for Cordys Analytics, I started working with them as a part-time A.I. Engineer. My responsibilities involve both A.I. research work, as well as assistance with the development of the company's main software product, an end-to-end online diagnostic service.

A.I. Intern Mar. 2024 - Aug. 2024

During my internship, I focused on the topic of "Noise Detection and Uncertainty Estimation in ECGs," applying deep learning techniques to identify noisy electrocardiograms. My main contributions and takeaways include:

- I familiarized myself with Out Of Distribution (OOD) detection methods and implemented various techniques from recent literature to improve the robustness and reliability of ECG noise detection models.
- I designed and conducted various experiments, testing different models on public and private ECG datasets to evaluate and optimize the performance of noise detection algorithms.
- o I gained firsthand experience in the dynamic startup environment at Cordys.
- I actively contributed to Cordy's ECGxAI package, a useful tool in the analysis and interpretation of ECG data using deep learning methods.

My strong performance and good work ethic during my internship resulted in me getting hired for a part-time A.I. Engineering role in the same company.

Maastricht University Maastricht, NL

Self-Learning Module Website Developer

Jul. 2024 - Aug. 2024

I developed and hosted on GitHub pages a self-learning module website template focused on Multivariable Calculus. I also wrote a Python script to convert \prescript{LTEX} to HTML.

Teaching Assistant Apr. 2023 - Feb. 2024

I was a teaching assistant for bachelor's mathematics courses such as Linear Algebra, Logic, Probability & Statistics and Multivariable Calculus.

Education

Maastricht University Maastricht, NL

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence

Sep. 2022 - Today

I have taken courses in topics such as Search Algorithms, Deep Learning, Autonomous Robotics Systems, Computer Vision, Data Mining, Text Mining and Natural Language Processing. Additionally, as a part of my degree, I participated in two research group projects. I am currently working on my master's thesis alongside my work at Cordys Analytics.

University of Cambridge Cambridge, UK

Master of Mathematics (bachelor's & integrated master's)

Oct. 2017 - Jul. 2021

In my two final years of study I mainly focused on Logic and Combinatorics, taking courses such as: Model Theory (on which I wrote my master's thesis), Topics in Combinatorics, Ramsey Theory, Additive Combinatorics, Logic and Set Theory, Graph Theory. Other topics I have taken include: Differential Equations, Statistics, Linear Algebra, Number Theory, Group/Ring/Module Theory, Real and Complex Analysis, Topology, Probability and Measure Theory, Linear Analysis, Differential Geometry.

Mandoulides Schools Thessaloniki, GR

Apolytirion of Geniko Lykeio (high-school diploma)

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2017

Due to my strong performance in school exams as well as extracuriccular maths and physics competitions (most notably winning a bronze medal in the 18th Junior Balkan Mathematical Olympiad, a gold medal in the 31st Greek Junior National Mathematical Olympiad and the first place in the 25th Panhellenic Physics Competition) I received a full scholarship throughout my years of study in Mandoulides Schools.

Skills

A.I. development: I have practical experience in developing A.I. algorithms for signal analysis, including ECG and audio signals. Moreover, for my current master's I have studied and worked on high-quality projects in various fields of A.I., including Text Mining & Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision and Robotics.

Python development: I have extensive experience in Python, having used it for integration and evaluation of A.I. algorithms in production, for A.I. research, as well as for multiple university and personal projects. In particular, I am familiar with software development standards such as Object Oriented Programming and unit testing, as well as many libraries commonly used in machine learning, such as PyTorch, PyTorch Lightning, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, etc.

Problem solving & mathematics: Having completed the 4-year Mathematics course at the University of Cambridge, which includes the highly competitive Part III course (selective 4th year integrated master's), I have developed excellent problem solving skills. Moreover, I have a strong command of various pure and applied mathematical areas, including probability and statistics.

Communication skills: My experiences working with a small multi-functional team in a startup and teaching courses from multiple faculties as a teaching assistant have helped me develop the ability to effectively communicate with people from different backgrounds and fields.

Web development: I have worked with HTML, CSS and JavaScript for personal projects as well as for developing a Self-Learning Module for the Multivariable Calculus course at the School of Business and Economics in Maastricht University.

Linux & bash scripting: I have some experience with Linux and bash scripting, both as a power user as well as a developer.

MATLAB: I have used MATLAB in multiple projects for my degree in Mathematics.

Awards

Awarus	
Association for Computing Machinery (student chapter), Aristotle University of Thessaloniki ACM AUTh Days of Coding, First place Team competition. Our submissions: Pk-470/acm-auth-days-of-coding	2022
Hellenic Society for Physics, Science and Education 26th Panhellenic Physics Competition, Third Prize	2016
Hellenic Mathematical Society 33rd Greek National Mathematical Olympiad, Silver Medal	2016
Kangourou Sans Frontieres Kangaroo Hellas Mathematical Competition, Distinction	2016
Mathematical Association of America American Mathematics Competition - AMC 10, Distinction Arrived in top 2.5% internationally.	2015
Young Gifted Mathematicians Marin Getaldić 4th Junior European Mathematical Cup, Third Prize	2015
Hellenic Mathematical Society 32nd Greek National Mathematical Olympiad, Silver Medal	2015
Hellenic Society for Physics, Science and Education 25th Panhellenic Physics Competition, First Place	2015
Union of Mathematicians of Macedonia 18th Junior Balkan Mathematical Olympiad, Bronze Medal	2014
Hellenic Mathematical Society 31st Greek Junior National Mathematical Olympiad, Gold Medal	2014
Hellenic Mathematical Society 30th Greek Junior National Mathematical Olympiad, Silver Medal	2013

Selected projects from my A.I. master's

Automatic Music Sheet Page Turner - Cosotogd/Music-Score-Localization-2.0 Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023 Our group developed an algorithm with the aim to localize a recorded song snippet as played by a human within the music score of the entire song. Our algorithm is based on the one developed for the app Shazam, while also including techniques such as Monte-Carlo Robot Localization.

Impasse AI - • pk-470/impasse-ai

Sep. 2022 - Oct. 2022

I created a search engine for the game Impasse by Mark Steere which uses Alpha-Beta search along with move ordering, iterative deepening and a transposition table. When matched with the engines of my classmates in a tournament my engine came 3rd overall, surpassing many engines which could search deeper within the allowed time due to being written in languages faster than Python.

Selected computational projects from my Mathematics bachelor's

Graph Colouring Mar. 2020 - Apr. 2020

I studied and implemented on MATLAB various techniques for efficiently bounding the chromatic number of a graph.

Simulation of Random Samples from Parametric Distributions

Dec. 2019 - Jan. 2020

I used MATLAB to study and visualise the behaviour of random variables sampled from various distributions (exponential, gamma, normal, chi-squared).

Ordinary Differential Equations

Mar. 2018 - Apr. 2018

I used MATLAB to study and compare three methods for solving ODEs (Leapfrog, Euler, RK4).

Essays & Presentations

Part III, University of Cambridge

Cambridge, UK

NIP Theories and O-minimality - • pk-470/nip-theories

Feb. 2021 - Apr. 2021

As a part of my master's in Mathematics I worked on an expository essay on Model Theory, a branch of Mathematical Logic. This essay required extensive independent research and study of multiple papers, which I then had to condense and combine into a coherent and focused text.

8th International Week Dedicated to Maths

Thessaloniki, GR

Inversion: Properties and Applications

Feb. 2016 - Mar. 2016

While still being a student in Mandoulides Schools I independently worked on and presented a project on the properties of geometric inversion and how it can be used to produce imaginative solutions to very hard competition problems.

Extracurricular projects

Supermod - Ppk-470/Supermod

2022

In order to teach myself Python I created a Discord bot whose duties include fetching and manipulating data from Google spreadsheets, extracting and formatting data from messages, interacting with the users and making posts periodically.

Languages

Greek (mother tongue), English (proficient), German (B1 level, can catch up if needed).

Additional skills & interests

Rowing: I was a member of the Emmanual College Boatclub in Cambridge and I rowed in the 2018 Fairbairn Cup.

Music: For the past 7 years I have been playing and writing music for the electric bass (mainly) and the guitar.

LATEX: I regularly use Latex to write technical and non-technical documents (including this one).